Terri Hammons

<u>terri@terrihammons.com</u> | 512-484-4092 http://terri-hammons-portfolio.herokuapp.com

Experienced library and information science professional with a strong background in research, writing, and content development. Additional skills and education in web development, providing a unique ability to merge research and information management strategies with technical execution.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Web Development, Full Stack Flex, The Coding Bootcamp at University of Texas (Jan-July 2017)

Master of Library and Information Science, University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology, University of Texas at Austin

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MySQL, APIs, MongoDB; Windows and Mac OS; MS Office + OneNote; Google Mail & Apps; Confluence, JIVE social platforms; SharePoint (calendars, workflows)

SAMPLE CODING WORK

INFOFINDER

http://authentical-infofinder.herokuapp.com/ A web app with a librarian-curated selection of authoritative information resources for use by educational content developers. Built on the MERN stack

RACETRACK

http://project-racetrack.herokuapp.com/ A group project to create a review site for triathlons, using JavaScript, Handlebars, and MySQL

MININGCRAFT

https://meador-mining-craft.herokuapp.com/ A fun little JavaScript/JQuery math game

EXPERIENCE

CONFERENCE PRODUCER

Healthcare Education Associates (A Division of Wilmington FRA), Remote • 2016

Extensive Research, Writing, Content Development, and Project Management in support of end-to-end production cycle for educational conferences and training sessions on healthcare topics

- Analyzed detailed technical information from interviews, customer surveys, and industry publications to identify topics for conferences.
 Distilled information into structured agendas and session descriptions
- Recruited industry executives and thought-leaders to serve as speakers and event chairpersons
- Supported sales team with research on leads for sponsorship opportunities
- Attended conferences on-site to facilitate venue set-up and overall event operation
- Composed copy for sales and marketing collateral, including conference webpages, brochures, email blasts, and telesales scripts
- Program examples at http://www.frallc.com/pdf/H421.pdf and http://www.frallc.com/pdf/H351.pdf

MANAGER-EDITORIAL SUPPORT SERVICES

(Fact Checking, Copyright Permissions, & Library Services)

Pearson, Austin, TX/Remote • 2006-2016

Team Leader and Manager, Accountable for the Processes and Resources to deliver fact checking, copyright permissions, and information services for educational assessment programs

- Successfully coordinated and prioritized fact checking and acquisition of copyright permissions for 25+ assessment projects, employing collaborative work methods to meet aggressive deadlines
- Supported all aspects of the fact checking and copyright permissions processes, from gathering project requirements to onboarding and training new team members
- Created a knowledge base prototype for the assessment division on the company's Jive social platform
- Developed training materials on research methods and evaluating information sources, and led training efforts for internal content development staff, outside vendors, and freelancers

FREELANCE/CONTRACT WORK

Permissions Consultant—Dec 2016-present, **QUAD Graphics**

Apply strong skills and knowledge in copyright permissions and text sourcing to "deep dive" audits of textbooks to identify and evaluate third-party content. Project deliverables include a methodical page-by-page review of each book, analysis of permissions status for all content, and population of detailed permissions spreadsheets.

Fact Check Researcher—July 2017-present Northwest

2017-present, Northwest Evaluation Association

Use authoritative web sources and library databases to research and verify facts and descriptive information in test items and stimuli for assessments. Suggest revisions and edits to language and structure of reading passages and test items.

Section Violinist—2000-present,

Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra, Laredo Philharmonic Orchestra

Orchestra musician for awardwinning, regional orchestras in south/central Texas. Performances with renowned soloists, including Itzhak Perlman, Joshua Bell, Van Cliburn, Andre Watts, Evelyn Glennie, and Edgar Meyer, and more.

- "Super searcher" for the team—tracked hard-to-find rights holders using biographical sources, public records, library databases, and other online sources
- Worked with Legal and Contracts groups to develop and implement the intellectual property policies and procedures
- Created a permissions audit process to ensure compliance with client contract requirements and copyright law
- Series of promotions to positions of increasing responsibility, including to team lead in 2007 and Senior Research Librarian in 2010.
 Subsequently promoted to team manager in 2010
- Editorial Services Employee of the Year; identified as "brave, creative, strategic and smart"

REFERENCE/TEXAS DOCUMENTS LIBRARIAN

Texas State Library and Archives Commission, Austin, TX • 2002-2006

Delivered Reference and Research Assistance to a Diverse Customer Base, including state employees, legislators, students, and members of the general public

- As part of a public-facing Reference team, key player in helping to meet the agency's legislatively mandated 95% customer satisfaction rate
- Collaborated with other Reference Team members to respond to approximately 600 written and telephone requests per month, covering topics including legislative history research, genealogical research, and queries on state government agencies. Trained and guided patrons in use of databases and library tools
- Assisted in developing and maintaining the Reference Department's electronic library of written responses to frequently asked questions
- Created and edited procedures documentation for the Texas government documents collection, and updated document records in the Sirsi WorkFlows system
- Selected for Employee of the Quarter award, and identified by colleagues as "highly resourceful" and a "master multitasker"

RESEARCH SPECIALIST

TManage, Austin, TX • 1999-2001

Created Company Knowledge and Information Resource Center, and provided information and knowledge management services for sales and marketing teams

- Developed and managed the services provided through the company Information Resource Center (IRC), including market research and competitive intelligence
- Managed the IRC budget and negotiated services with research analyst groups such as Gartner and Forrester. Trained staff on use of LexisNexis and other research databases
- Wrote and distributed internal company newsletter
- Worked on special projects such as finding information for company bylined articles, and producing fact sheets used in sales efforts
- Created market and industry fact sheets used by company executives for regional and national events and conference presentations
- Coordinated primary research efforts, including focus group studies and surveys